PATRICK ABU

Email: patrickabu97@gmail.com

Accra, Ghana

Phone: +233546332483

Self-motivated Web Developer with knowledge in HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript (JQuery, Node.JS), and Computer Technician with over 4 years of systems upgrade and network component installation experience. Highly knowledgeable in demonstrating software features to employees. Competent Computer Scientist with a background in email account and connectivity set up for large organizations, well-versed in assisting users with diverse computer systems, mobile devices, and peripheral equipment problems. Familiar with security standards and usability optimization. Effectively operates autonomously to debug, troubleshoot and fix concerns.

EXPERIENCE

2020 - 2022

WEB DEVELOPMENT,

- E-Commerce Website
- · Weather Website
- · Dating Website
- Flower Website

JUNE 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2019

IT INTERN, KOTOKA INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT

- Collaborated to assist support protocol development and offered consultation based on cross-functional knowledge.
- Supported Electrical Department handling technology rollout and maintenance.
- Aided problem resolution measures and suggested patches and hardware, software, and network troubleshooting alternatives.
- Built and provided basic end-user troubleshooting and desktop support on Windows.
- Trained and supported end-users with software, hardware, and network standards and use processes.
- Identified and solved technical issues using a variety of diagnostic tools and tactics.

2020 - 2021

IT TECHNICIAN, ACCRA TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY

- Cataloging both new and old books into the new Koha Library Software.
- Investigating and correcting problems with printers, copiers, and other peripheral devices.
- Executing various techniques, including designing flyers and brochures to help with seminars and marketing of the library on the library's social media platforms.

- Delivering network technology training to junior team members and end-users, enhancing knowledgebase and team productivity.
- Assessing system hardware and software, and suggesting modifications to reduce lag time and improve overall speed.
- Setting up hardware and software in optimal configurations to meet network performance requirements.
- Educating students on how to use the Koha Software for research purposes.

OCTOBER 2019 - MARCH 2020

IT SUPPORTS ENGINEER, INFOSOURCE LIMITED

- Followed up with clients to verify optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution.
- Helped streamline repair processes and update procedures for support action consistency.
- Created support documentation that empowered and enabled the user community to extend skills, leverage system features, and find resolutions to questions without intervention from the support team.

2018 - 2019

ICT ASSISTANT AND LABORATORY TECHNICIAN, MOTHERCARE INTERNATIONAL

- Kept ICT laboratory in compliance with all applicable guidelines and laws.
- Oversaw items in inventory and reordered before supplies diminished.
- Teaching the students
- Set and oversaw quality assurance guidelines for laboratory work. ☐ Assisted in servicing of computers.

2015 - 2018

PRODUCTION MANAGER, SPECIAL COOL DRINKING WATER

- Directed manufacturing process and operational efficiency procedures to achieve the goal of first run capability.
- Determined suitable crew requirements, scheduled employees, and worked with Human Resources to meet changing production schedules.
- Completed and recorded all recycling and rework documentation with a high degree of accuracy.
- Planned, directed, coordinated, and assigned manpower to meet aggressive production schedules.
- Designed and implemented a new production schedule to reduce loss in labor and inventory.
- Created and updated department work instructions and reports regularly.
- Sourced materials to keep up with production goals and meet customer demands.
- Managed and implemented marketing activities through research and strategic planning,
- Implemented quality improvement changes to minimize product defect rates.
- Applied lean practices to balance workflow and eliminate unnecessary steps.

EDUCATION

2020 - 2022

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY, ACCRA TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY
SECOND CLASS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

08-2020
HIGHER NATIONAL DIPLOMA, ACCRA TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY
SECOND CLASS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2

SKILLS

- Web Development
 - Software Design
- Network Configuration
 - Software Configuration
 - Wireless Networking
 - Desktop Technical Support
- Virus and prevention
- Mobile Device Deployment
- Peripheral Repair
- Hardware and software installation

REFERENCES

- Sheila Acquah Asare
 The Director
 Mothercare International School <u>sacquahasare@gmail.com</u>
 0244698011
- Samuel Brohm
 Manager at the Electrical Department
 Kotoka International Airport
 0244658565
- Dr. Florence Plockey
 University Librarian Head
 Accra Technical University
 0505284495

Agbottah Senanu
 Director
 Infosource Limited
 0244363001